Juanita McHenry

809 Francis Street, Lancaster TX 75146 Cell: 469-955-0961 - jmchenry66@yahoo.com

Summary

Certified Nursing Assistant with 20+ years experience in fast-paced environment handling confidential paperwork, administering medication and providing quality patient care. Skilled in technical, clerical and patient support. Strong ability to communicate clearly and effectively to patients and staff. Certified Nursing Assistant with home health care and hospice care experience. Proven record of reliability and strong ability to establish rapport with patients, family and staff.

Skills

- Health and wellness expertise
- Medication administration expert
- Broad medical terminology knowledge
- Committed to compliance reporting
- Colostomy care familiarity

- Computerized charting specialist
- Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS) certification
- Wound cleaning/care expertise
- Flow sheet charting
- Acute and rehabilitative care

Experience

Order Picker/Packer seasonal

November 2017 to December 2017

Kohl's eFulfillment Center — DeSoto, TX

Unloaded, picked, staged and loaded products for shipping.

Oversaw special orders and after-hours, urgent shipping jobs.

Oversaw warehousing and storage practices and housekeeping.

Nurse Aide

January 2015 to November 2017

Lakes Regional MHMR Center — Waxahachie, TX

Observed and documented patient status and reported patient complaints to the case manager.

Read and recorded temperature, pulse and respiration.

Massaged patients and applied preparations and treatments, such as liniment, alcohol rubs and heat-lamp stimulation.

Prepared patient rooms prior to their arrival.

Assisted with adequate nutrition and fluid intake.

Planned, prepared and served meals and snacks according to prescribed diets.

Performed household tasks such as laundry, dusting, washing dishes and vacuuming.

Positioned residents for comfort and to prevent skin pressure problems.

Assisted with transferring residents in and out of wheelchairs and adaptive equipment.

Charted daily information on the residents such as mood changes, mobility activity, eating percentages, and daily inputs and outputs.

Certified Nurses Aide

October 2012 to December 2014

Monticello West — Dallas, TX

Observed and documented patient status and reported patient complaints to the case manager.

Read and recorded temperature, pulse and respiration.

Prepared patient rooms prior to their arrival.

Support duties for diagnostic and technical treatment procedures, such as setting up and operating special medical equipment and apparatus.

Assisted with adequate nutrition and fluid intake.

Planned, prepared and served meals and snacks according to prescribed diets.

Cleaned and organized patients' living quarters.

Positioned residents for comfort and to prevent skin pressure problems.

Performed household tasks such as laundry, dusting, washing dishes and vacuuming. Assisted with transferring residents in and out of wheelchairs and adaptive equipment.

PCT

April 2007 to April 2011

Kindred Hospital Tarrant County - Arlington — Arlington, TX

Positioned patients for optimal comfort before procedures.

Prepared equipment and positioned patients for cardiac catheterization and other invasive procedures.

Recorded patient histories and filed supporting clinical data and diagnosis.

Monitored patient stability by checking vital signs and weight. 10 years experience as a patient care technician.

PCT

September 2004 to December 2006

Select Specialty Hospital - Desoto — Desoto, TX

L-tech setting)Responsible for vitals, wts. feeding, grooming, intake and output. Worked codes, worked ICU and floors. Assistes with wound care worked directly with LVN and RN doing patient care.

Education and Training

High School Diploma: Recommended, 1985

LG Pinkston High School — Dallas, TX, United States

Certificate: Certified Nurses Aide, 1988

Nurses Aide Academy — Lancaster, TX, United States

Coursework in Acute Care Nursing

Hair cutting theory: Class A Barber-Stylist, 1999 Dallas Barber Shop — Dallas, TX, United States

Hair treatment training Sanitation training

Haircutting and Chemical Services training

Activities and Honors

Acute Care Nurses (10 years)

Home Health Aides (22 years)

Nursing Aides, Orderlies, and Attendants (22 year)

Class A Barber License(22+ years)